today we are going to discuss what could
potentially be one of the most
revolutionary programming languages Mojo
it's been a long time since I've seen so
many people excited about a programming
language So today we're going to learn
what Mojo is why people are losing their
minds over it and what the code looks
like but first let's talk about python
python is one of the most used
programming languages in the world
because it's very beginner friendly and
easy to read and write because of this
it's used by all sorts of communities
web developers data scientists marketers
AI enthusiasts Etc but python is slow
super slow hundreds of times slower than
C plus plus or rust C plus plus and rust
among others are what we use when we
want speed when we want to be as close
to the metal as possible when we want to
use all the cores when we want to have
full control another problem with python
is that is hard to distribute if I
finish a Python program and I want to
give it to you to run it you will have
to install python in your machine as
well as all the other packages my
program needs to run enter Mojo Mojo is
not a completely new programming
language Mojo is a super set of python
being a superset of python means that it
builds on top of python it uses all the
python features and syntax that
everybody knows and it adds a ton of new
much powerful features to it Mojo makes
python as fast and Powerful as C plus
and rust apart from a couple of things
Mojo and python syntax are the same this
code will run in both Mojo and python
just fine Mojo also aims to be fully
python compatible which means that only
already existing python packages in
libraries will all work in Mojo by
default this is how we can import python
libraries in the case of numpy from a
Mojo program module uses that that Mojo
file extension as well as the dot fire
Emoji extension which I think is pretty
cool even though Mojo understands python
code that doesn't mean that the code
will automatically run fast if we want
to enable fast mode in Mojo we have to
use different keywords for example this
python function will run in module but
it won't run fast to make it faster to
enable fast mode we have to change the
code to this as you can see instead of
using def to define a function we use
the new keyword FN and as you can also
see we have to tell Mojo that the name
parameter is of type string the if and
keyword is very powerful when you
declare a function with FN the Mojo
compiler can make strong guarantees
about the function's behavior and it can
optimize it at compile time it is the
same with classes instead of writing our
classes like this we can use the new
struct keyword by swapping class for
struct and death for FN Mojo can
optimize our data structures at compile
time Mojo also introduces two new
keywords that python did not have before
let's Environ using let nvar we can
create immutable and mutable variable we
can use let for immutable variables and
we can use VAR for mutable ones another
cool thing about Mojo is that because it
is compiled when you finish a Mojo
program you can package it all into one
file and deploy module also comes with
an ownership and borrow checker for
memory safety following the ideas of Ros
and because it uses mlir a compiler
infrastructure Mojo is able to do
parallel processing compared to python
that is single threaded making mojo
super appealing for AI Mojo is created
by Chris Ladner a legendary developer
that in the past co-founded llvm the
silang compiler and the Swift
programming language Mojo is still
pretty new the current version is 0.1 it
does not Support classes yet and it's
not even open source to try Mojo you
have to sign up with your email to get
an invitation for the Mojo playground
the project is in its infancy but
nevertheless people are very excited at
the idea of being able to ride super
fast code using a syntax that is easy
and familiar without compromising access
to the gigantic python ecosystem now I
want to know what you think are you
excited about Mojo what do you think
about it did you try it are you gonna
try it let me know in the comments below
and don't forget that if you want to
learn things like JavaScript python
react react native gold dark flutter
among many many others for absolutely
free all you have to do is click the
link below to join any of our many free
courses that you can take right now for
absolutely free with me click the link
below and I will see you there
see you on the next one bye
thanks